hellointern.com 2008-10-02

# HelloIntern - One stop shop for Internships,Summer Jobs,Practical Traning and more...

**Overview**

At HelloIntern we are committed to provide an easy, and safe environment for students to get internships of their choice, and for organisations to find relevant interns. Protecting their privacy is extremely important to us and is one of our top objectives when designing the website and its infrastructure. We recognize and respect the importance of maintaining the privacy of our customers and look forward to maintaining the trust in our business relationship. We have created this privacy policy to disclose and explain you why we gather customer and member information, what information we collect, how we collect it, what we use the information for and how you can instruct us to limit the use of that information. We have designed our procedures and processes for handling your data with the same high quality care and security that we would expect our own personal data to be handled.

HelloIntern knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust that we will do so carefully and sensibly. At HelloIntern, we let you retain as much control as possible over your personal information. However, you may not visit and use our site at anytime without telling us who you are or revealing the required information about yourself. This notice describes our privacy policy. By visiting our site, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**1.** What Information do we gather?

We collect and store only a very limited amount of data and personal information necessary to process your account and to operate and improve our services. You can be assured that your information is protected. Your individual, and personal data will not be distributed.

We will retain information you may have requested us to remove if, in our discretion, retention of the information is necessary to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, or to enforce the Terms of Services agreement. Furthermore, your information is never completely removed from our databases due to technical and legal constraints. For example, we will not remove your information from our back-up storage systems.

The personal information about you, that hellointern may possibly collect are:

**Email** We collect and store your e-mail address when you provide it to us at the time of registration. The email address is used for correspodence betwwen the user and us. It may also be used to keep you updated about our website.

**Name** We collect and store your name when you provide it to us at the time of registration. The name is required so that we may identify you properly and respectfully.

**Address** We collect and store the postal address (town, city, state, country and postal code) at the time of registration. The addresses are used as a backup contact in case of emergency.

**Phone Number** We collect the phone number at the time of registration and will only use it in the rare emergency that we need to contact you by phone, such as if we suspect that someone may be using your account fraudulently. These calls will not be made to sell you anything. We may collect your mobile phone number and to enable services for your mobile device.

**Password** We collect and store your password so that you may access your account securely at the time of registration.

**Friends' E-mail Addresses** We collect your friend's email addresses and names when you use our Tell a Friend feature or add their details in the address book. Names and e-mail addresses are stored for the purpose of making it easy for you to use them again in the future.

**Feedback** We collect your feedback, suggestions, and information that you give to us, including information about your preferences.

**Resume** We collect your resume at the time of registration, or you may upload it while updating your profile. It is used by companies associated with us to shortlist candidates for their interns.

**Miscellaneous** We also gather or may gather certain information about your use of our site, such as what areas you visit and what services you access. Moreover, there is information about your computer hardware and software that is or may be collected by us. This information can include without limitation your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times and referring website addresses.

We may sometimes afford you the opportunity to provide descriptive, cultural, behavioral and preferential and/or life style information about yourself, but it is solely up to you whether you furnish such information. If you do provide such information, you are thereby consenting to the use of that information in accordance with the policies and practices described in this Statement. For example, such information may be used for the purpose of determining your potential interest in receiving email or other communications about particular products or services.

Please remember that if you post any of your personal information in public areas of hellointern.com, such as in online forums or chat rooms, such information may be collected and used by others over whom hellointern.com.com has no control. We are not responsible for the use made by third parties of information you post or otherwise make available in public areas of this website.

Since we believe that managing your career is a life-long process, we retain indefinitely all the information we gather about you in an effort to make your repeat use with us more efficient, practical, and relevant. Of course, you can correct or update your account profile and resume at any time. Moreover, you can delete your resume from our online database or close your account at any time, in which event we will remove all our copies of your resume and your account profile information except for an archival copy which is not accessible on the internet.

**2.** Who collects the information?  

We will collect personally identifiable information about you only as part of a voluntary registration process, on-line survey, or contest. Visitors of hellointern who do not have hellointern accounts are not required to log into the website or provide any personal information to view our website. We only collect personal information from users who are not hellointern subscribers when they sign up for a newsletter or otherwise wish to communicate with others on the website. Please note that we have no control over any information that is disclosed publicly. You should exercise caution when disclosing your personal information at places in the website which are accessible to anyone.

**3.** What are various technical issues you must be aware of?  

**Search Engines** Some search engines and websites not affiliated with hellointern, may cache, archive, or otherwise store hellointern pages. Hellointern does not have control of the information or pages on those websites.

**Automatic Information** We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with us. For example, like many web sites, we use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your Web browser accesses hellointern’s site.

**About Cookies** Like many web sites, we set and use cookies to enhance your user experience, such as retaining your personal settings. Advertisements may appear on our web site and, if so, may set and access cookies on your computer and is subject to the privacy policy of those parties providing the advertisement. However, the companies serving the advertising do not have access to our cookies. These companies usually use non-personally identifiable or anonymous codes to obtain information about your visits to our site.

**4.** How do we ensure your security?  

**Password-Protection** When you create your hellointern account, you choose a private password for yourself. Be sure to keep your password confidential, safe, and secure. If someone knows your password, they have access to your account and your personal information, and you are responsible for their activities. If you feel that your password is no longer private and confidential, be sure to change it, or send a message to hellointern requesting your password be changed. If you feel that an unauthorized person has accessed your account, contact hellointern immediately. To ensure that you have properly logged out of your account, be sure to close your browser, especially on public computers, such as those found in libraries, schools and cyber-cafes.

**Links to Third-party Websites** hellointern, its subscribers, and visitors, may provide links to third-party websites, which may have privacy policies different from the privacy policy on hellointern. We are not responsible for, nor have any control over, the privacy policies of those third-party websites, and encourage you to read the privacy policies of each and every website you visit. When you click on links to other websites, those websites may attach a cookie to your hard drive and may collect information about you. hellointern makes no claims or representations about what information those websites do or do not collect about you. Please review any Terms of Services Agreements and Privacy Policies of those other websites to learn about their data collection and data use practices.

**Personal Information and Data** As per our Terms and Services Agreement, you are solely responsible for, and hellointern is not liable for, the personal information and other materials that you post, upload, submit, and otherwise make available on the website, including areas of the website that are available to the public. We have no control over and cannot protect personal information that you disclose in public areas of hellointern. If you disclose your personal information in public areas, it may be collected and used by third parties, without our or your knowledge.

**Advertising** Hellointern may offer sponsorships, contests, promotions, and advertisements in the periodic newsletter and on areas of the website that are available to visitors for free. Hellointern will not rent, share, sell, or otherwise disclose your personal data to any third party for marketing purposes. Hellointern will not send you unsolicited e-mail communications for marketing purposes. When you participate in a promotion, contest, or survey, we may ask you for personal information. Participation in any survey or contest is completely voluntary and you therefore have a choice whether or not to disclose this information.

**Law Enforcement** Hellointern will not rent, share, sell, or otherwise disclose your personal data to any third party, except for law enforcement purposes, as stated in the hellointern Terms of Services agreement. Hellointern may disclose information about its users to law enforcement officers or others, in the good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary to:  
* Respond to subpoenas, court orders, judicial proceedings, or other legal processes  
* Enforce our Terms of Services agreement  
* Respond to claims that any text, or other material violates the rights of third-parties  
* Or protect the rights, property, or personal safety of hellointern, its users, or the general public  

No one from hellointern will ever call you and ask for your password. If you are ever contacted by someone claiming to be an employee of hellointern, and the person asks you for your personal billing information or password, do not give them any information; instead, report the incident to us with as much detail as possible, and we will investigate.

**5.** How can you correct inaccuracies in the information?  

You can help hellointern maintain the accuracy of your personal information by:  
* Notifying us when you change your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, or your newsletter preferences  
* Update your information from the My Profile page  
* Contacting us at any time via our Contact Us page  
If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter, you may opt-out by following the instructions in the newsletter or by sending us your request via our Contact Us page.

**6.** How do we handle Changes to this Policy?  

**Notification** As the hellointern website continues to develop, we will add new features, and we may change the type of information we collect or the method by which the information is collected. We will update this privacy policy to reflect any changes, and we will provide you notice of significant changes to the privacy policy by posting notice at hellointern.com and through other methods as appropriate.

**Policy Differences** If we update our privacy policy, any information you have provided us before the policy change will be used in accordance with the privacy policy in effect when your information was collected. If we are going to use your personal information in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will notify you via e-mail. You will have a choice as to whether or not we can use your information in this different manner. If you no longer have an active or valid account, then you will not be contacted, and your personal information not be used. If we make any material changes in our privacy policy that do not affect your personal information already stored in our database, we will post notification on our website notifying you of the change. In some cases when we post a notice, we will also e-mail users who have opted to receive communications notifying them of the changes in our privacy practices.
